Guide to the Hart Crane Collection
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
- John Baker Papers, 1910-72; Series I; 1.25; (4 boxes)
  - WRITINGS
    - "Hart Crane Tries Advertising": Unfinished Draft, n.d. (Box 3, Folder 118-22)
    - Notes, n.d. (Box 3, Folder 123-24)
  - OTHER PAPERS
    - Advertising
      - Advertising agencies: Manhattan Classified Telephone Directory, 1928 (Box 4, Folder 125)
      - Advertising influences on Hart Crane, 1900-26, n.d. (Box 4, Folder 126)
      - Cowley, Malcolm: Ad for Obelisk Waterproofing Company, 1925 (Box 4, Folder 127)
      - Crane, Hart [?]: "Barreled Sunlight", 1923-24 (Box 4, Folder 128)
        See also: Box 13, folder 373
      - Crane, Hart: "Bathing by the Kalendar", 1922 (Box 4, Folder 129)
      - Crane, Hart: "Bathsheba's Bath", 1922 (Box 4, Folder 130)
      - Crane, Hart: "Community Plate"
        See: Box 13, folder 374
      - Crane, Hart: Jacket description for Waldo Frank: A Study, 1923 (Box 4, Folder 131)
      - Crane, Hart [?]: Pittsburgh Plate Glass and Pittsburgh Water Heater, 1922-23 (Box 4, Folder 132)
      - Crane in Advertising: miscellaneous (Box 4, Folder 133)
      - "Framed Mirrors" (Pittsburgh Plate Glass Company Catalog), 1923 (Box 4, Folder 134)
      - Hubbard, Elbert: advertising copies, 1910-15 (Box 4, Folder 135)
      - Hubbard, Elbert: "A Little Journey to Clarence Crane's Chocolate Studio", 1914 (Box 4, Folder 136)
      - Hubbard, Elbert: miscellaneous, 1913, n.d. (Box 4, Folder 137-38)
      - Little Review ads, 1919 (Box 4, Folder 139)
      - Sweet's Architectural Catalogue, 1925 (Box 4, Folder 140-41)
      - Thomas' Wholesale Grocery... register, 1924 (Box 4, Folder 142)
    - Biographical Material
      - Artists and advertisers (Box 4, Folder 143)
      - Hart Crane, 1932, 1969, n.d. (Box 4, Folder 144)
    - Photographs
      - Birthplace of Hart Crane, 1967 (Box 4, Folder 145)
      - Frank, Waldo (copy of photo by Stieglitz), 1920 (Box 4, Folder 146)
      - Patno, Stanley, n.d. (Box 4, Folder 147)
    - Printed Material
      - Cleveland, Ohio: street map (Box 4, Folder 148)
      - Erie and N. Y. Central Railroad Maps, 1904, 1927 (Box 4, Folder 149)
      - Garretsville, Ohio: assessment records, 1895-1967 (Box 4, Folder 150-51)
      - Garretsville, Ohio: Centennial Souvenir Program, 1964 (Box 4, Folder 152)
      - Manhattan and the Bronx: street map (Box 4, Folder 153)
      - The William Sommer Memorial Exhibition Catalogue, 1950 (Box 4, Folder 154)
    - Writings of Others
      - Christy, George. Essence of Old Kentucky, n.d. (Box 4, Folder 155)
      - Crane, Hart. Letters, 1920-27 (Box 4, Folder 156)
      - Crane, Hart. "Poster" (copy), n.d. (Box 4, Folder 157)
      - Crane, Hart. "Recitation" (copy), n.d. (Box 4, Folder 158)
      - Crane, Hart. Miscellaneous writings, 1929, n.d. (Box 4, Folder 159)
      - Josephson, Matthew. "The Great American Billposter", 1922 (Box 4, Folder 160)
      - Rowland, Mabel. Bert Williams: Son of Laughter, 1923 (Box 4, Folder 161)
      - Unterecker, John. "The Architecture of 'The Bridge'", 1962 (Box 4, Folder 162)
- Philip Horton Papers, 1919-39; Series II; 1.25; (3 boxes)
  Series II, Philip Horton Papers, is divided into six subseries: Philip Horton Correspondence, Miscellaneous Correspondence, Hart Crane Correspondence, Writings, Writings of Others, and Other Printed Material. Arrangement within each of these subseries is alphabetical by surname, title, or assigned heading.
  - PHILIP HORTON CORRESPONDENCE
    - Adams, William, 1936 (Box 5, Folder 163)
      See also: Box 5, folder 205
    - Anderson, Sherwood, 1936 Jan 2 (Box 5, Folder 164)
    - Barnes, Djuna, 1935 Jul 24 (Box 5, Folder 165)
    - Birss, Jack, 1934-35 (Box 5, Folder 166)
    - Brown, William Slater, 1935-36 (Box 5, Folder 167)
    - Burnett, Whit, 1936 Nov 25 (Box 5, Folder 168)
    - Bynner, Witter, 1936 Jan 29 (Box 5, Folder 169)
    - Coleman, E. Holmes, 1937 Nov 12 (Box 5, Folder 170)
    - Coulehan, Peg, 1937 Jul 20 (Box 5, Folder 171)
    - Cowley, Malcolm, 1937 (Box 5, Folder 172)
    - Cowley, Peggy Baird, n.d. (Box 5, Folder 173)
    - Crane, Bessie Meacham, 1935-36 (Box 5, Folder 174)
    - Crosby, Caresse (The Black Sun Press), 1935 Nov 25 (Box 5, Folder 175)
    - Damon, [Foster], 1939 Jun 14 (Box 5, Folder 175a)
    - Deming, Zell Hart, n.d. (Box 5, Folder 176)
    - Dietz, Lorna, 1936, n.d. (Box 5, Folder 177)
    - Feyling, Peggy Baird Cowley
      See: Cowley, Peggy Baird
    - Fisher, William Murrell, 1936, 1939 (Box 5, Folder 178)
    - Fitzgerald, M. Eleanor, 1935 Jun 29 (Box 5, Folder 179)
    - Frank, Waldo, 1935-37 (Box 5, Folder 180)
    - Gund, Herman (Alcestis Press), 1936 Nov 5 (Box 5, Folder 181)
    - Hamill, Esther Dette, 1938 Mar 22 (Box 5, Folder 182)
    - Harris, Robert J., 1937 May 20 (Box 5, Folder 183)
    - Hersher, Ruth, 1939 (Box 5, Folder 184)
    - Hirsch, Stefan, 1936 Apr 13 (Box 5, Folder 185)
    - Horton, Everett J., 1937 (Box 5, Folder 186)
    - Josephson, Matthew, 1935-37 (Box 5, Folder 187)
    - Kellogg, Edith S., 1936 Jan 19 (Box 5, Folder 188)
    - Kline, Ruth Hubbard, 1937 May 27 (Box 5, Folder 189)
    - Lasch, Helene Dorothy, 1938 Feb 16 (Box 5, Folder 190)
    - Latimer, Ronald Lane (The Alcestis Press), 1936, 1938 (Box 5, Folder 191)
    - Lescaze, William, 1936-37 (Box 5, Folder 192)
    - MacCown, Eugene, 1936 Feb 10 (Box 5, Folder 193)
    - MacKaye, Percy, 1936 Jan 5 (Box 5, Folder 194)
    - MacLeish, Archibald, 1925 Jun 24 (Box 5, Folder 195)
    - Madden, N. B., 1935 (Box 5, Folder 196)
    - Manchester, Earl N., 1936 (Box 5, Folder 197)
    - Moe, Henry Allen (Guggenheim Foundation), 1936 Jan 4 (Box 5, Folder 198)
    - Monroe, Harriet (Poetry Magazine), 1935 May 17 (Box 5, Folder 199)
    - Morley, F. V., 1937 Jun 16 (Box 5, Folder 200)
    - Munson, Gorham, 1936 Aug 21 (Box 5, Folder 201)
    - Norton, W. W., 1935, 1937 (Box 5, Folder 202)
    - O'Neill, Eugene, 1936 (Box 5, Folder 203)
    - Opffer, Emil, 1935 Jul 25 (Box 5, Folder 204)
      See also: folder 276 (letter of Nov 1927)
    - Packard, Peggy Meras, 1935, n.d. (Box 5, Folder 205)
    - Pearson, Norman Holmes, 1937 Sep 15 (Box 5, Folder 206)
    - Percival, Dr. [?], 1936 Jan 21 (Box 5, Folder 207)
    - Phillips, Howard S. ( Mexican Life ), 1935 Nov 20 (Box 5, Folder 208)
    - Porter, Katherine Anne, 1935, 1937 (Box 5, Folder 209)
    - Reque, O. F., 1937 Dec 6 (Box 5, Folder 210)
    - Riding, Laura, 1936-37 (Box 5, Folder 211)
    - Rodman, Selden, 1937 May 21 (Box 5, Folder 212)
    - Rutledge, Archibald, 1937 May 25 (Box 5, Folder 213)
    - Satterwaite, J. C., 1936 Aug 3 (Box 5, Folder 214)
    - Sawyer, Noble, n.d. (Box 5, Folder 215)
    - Schmitt, Carl, 1935 Oct 23 (Box 5, Folder 216)
    - Schneider, Isidor, 1935 May 16 (Box 5, Folder 217)
    - Seaver, Edwin, 1936 Jun 10 (Box 5, Folder 218)
    - Simpson, Eyler, 1936 Jan 11 (Box 5, Folder 219)
    - Simpson, Lesley Byrd, 1936 (Box 5, Folder 220)
    - Simpson, Marian, 1936 Jun 19 (Box 5, Folder 221)
    - Simpson, Mrs. T. W. (Sally), 1935 (Box 5, Folder 222)
    - Smith, Elizabeth, 1936 (Box 5, Folder 223)
    - Smith, Harrison, 1936 Jan 21 (Box 5, Folder 224)
    - Spencer (Evans), Claire, 1936, n.d. (Box 5, Folder 225)
    - Tate, Allen, 1935-37 (Box 5, Folder 226)
    - Toomer, Jean, 1936 Jan 22 (Box 5, Folder 227)
    - Underwood, Wilbur, 1935, n.d. (Box 5, Folder 228)
    - Vannatta, Thomas A., 1937, Oct 19 (Box 5, Folder 229)
    - Van Vuren, Mary, n.d. (Box 5, Folder 230)
    - Wade, James P., 1937 Oct 17 (Box 5, Folder 231)
    - Warren, Robert Penn, 1936 (Box 5, Folder 232)
    - Weinstock, Herbert, 1937 May 19 (Box 5, Folder 233)
    - Wiegand, Charmion von, 1936 Mar 5 (Box 5, Folder 234)
    - Williams, William Carlos, 1935 Oct 2 (Box 5, Folder 235)
    - Winters, Yvor, 1935-37 (Box 5, Folder 236)
    - Wright, William H., 1935-36 (Box 5, Folder 237)
    - Zinsser, Hans, 1935 Aug 13 (Box 5, Folder 238)
    - Unidentified ["Elizabeth"], 1937 (Box 5, Folder 239)
  - MISCELLANEOUS CORRESPONDENCE
    - Brenner, Anita to Mrs. Grace Crane., [1932] Sep 3 (Box 5, Folder 240)
    - Cowley, Peggy Baird to Anita Brenner, [1932?] Sep 28 (Box 5, Folder 241)
    - Kraft, Ona
      See: Box 5, folder 237
    - Morley, F. V. to W. W. Norton, 1937 May 31 (Box 5, Folder 242)
    - Norton, W. W. to Selden Rodman, 1937 Jun 11 (Box 5, Folder 243)
    - Norton, W. W. to Willard Thorp, 1932 May 25 (Box 5, Folder 243)
    - Parks, Edd Winfield to W. W. Norton, 1937 May 19 (Box 5, Folder 244)
    - Rodman, Selden to W. W. Norton, 1937 May 23 (Box 5, Folder 245)
    - Tate, Allen to W. Slater Brown (excerpt), 1932 May 28 (Box 5, Folder 246)
    - Thorp, Willard to W. W. Norton, 1937 May 23 (Box 5, Folder 247)
    - Weinstock, Herbert to W. W. Norton, 1937 May 19 (Box 5, Folder 248)
    - Welch, Porter S. to Storer Lunt (W. W. Norton & Co.), 1937 May 24 (Box 5, Folder 249)
  - HART CRANE CORRESPONDENCE
    - Brown, William Slater and Sue (Jenkins) Brown, 1923-31 (Box 6, Folder 250)
    - Cowley, Malcolm, 1923-32 (Box 6, Folder 251)
    - Cowley, Peggy Baird, 1931-32 (Box 6, Folder 252)
      See also: Box 6, folder 251
    - Curtis, Charles W., 1926 Nov 10 (Box 6, Folder 253)
    - Deming, Zell Hart, 1928 (Box 6, Folder 254)
    - Dietz, Lorna, 1929-32, n.d. (Box 6, Folder 255)
    - Flynn, Bina (property deed), 1925 Oct 13 (Box 6, Folder 256)
    - Frank, Waldo, 1922-31, n.d. (Box 6, Folder 257-59)
    - Kahn, Otto, 1927, n.d. (Box 6, Folder 260)
    - Monroe, Harriet, 1926-31 (Box 6, Folder 261)
    - Munson, Gorham, 1919-28 (Box 6, Folder 262-69)
    - Rychtarik, Richard and Charlotte, 1923-32 (Box 6, Folder 270-71)
    - Stieglitz, Alfred, 1923-26 (Box 6, Folder 272)
    - Stockwell, E. A., 1928 (Box 6, Folder 273)
    - Tate, Allen and Caroline, 1922-30, n.d. (Box 6, Folder 274)
    - Underwood, Wilbur, 1920-32 (Box 6, Folder 275-79)
    - Weinstock, Herbert, 1930 (Box 6, Folder 280)
    - Winters, Yvor, 1927 May 24 (Box 6, Folder 281)
    - Wright, William, 1918-31 (Box 6, Folder 282)
  - WRITINGS
    - Brief on Crane, n.d. (Box 7, Folder 283)
    - Influences in Hart Crane's Poetry, n.d. (Box 7, Folder 284)
    - Notes, n.d. (Box 7, Folder 285-88)
    - Notes from William Wright's essay, n.d. (Box 7, Folder 289)
    - [Empty folder] (Box 7, Folder 290)
    - [Empty folder] (Box 7, Folder 291)
    - [Empty folder] (Box 7, Folder 292)
    - [Empty folder] (Box 7, Folder 293)
  - WRITINGS OF OTHERS
    - Crane, A. E.: miscellaneous writings, n.d. (Box 7, Folder 294)
    - Crane, Frederic Jason: poems, n.d. (Box 7, Folder 295)
      See also: folder 294
    - Crane, Hart: "General Aims and Theories", 1925 (Box 7, Folder 296)
    - Crane, Hart: miscellaneous poems, n.d. (Box 7, Folder 297)
    - Crosby, Harry: "Shadows of the Sun" excerpts), n.d. (Box 7, Folder 298)
    - Rodman, Selden: review of Horton, Hart Crane, n.d. (Box 7, Folder 299)
    - Weinstock, Herbert: "The Collected Poems of Hart Crane", n.d. (Box 7, Folder 300)
  - OTHER PRINTED MATERIAL
    - Hart Crane: obituaries, 1932 (Box 7, Folder 301)
    - W. P. A. Federal Music Project: program, 1936 (Box 7, Folder 302)
- Norman Holmes Pearson Material, Dates 1916-31; Series III; 0.25; (1 box)
  Series III, Norman Holmes Pearson Material, consists of Hart Crane correspondence arranged alphabetically by surname.
  - Crane, Bess Meacham, 1931-32, n.d. (Box 8, Folder 303)
  - Crane, Bess Meacham (copies), 1931-32, n.d. (Box 8, Folder 304)
  - Crane, C. A., 1916-32 (Box 8, Folder 305-07)
  - Crane, C. A. (copies), 1916-32 (Box 8, Folder 308-09)
  - Pound, Ezra Portsmouth, Gerard Vernon Wallop (Lord Lymington), 1918, n.d. (Box 8, Folder 310)
- Brom Weber Papers, Dates 1910-32; Series IV; 1.25; (3 boxes)
  Series IV, Brom Weber Papers, is divided into two subseries, Writings and Papers. Writings consists of chronologically arranged Hart Crane correspondence and a final draft for Weber's book Hart Crane's Letters (with copies of many of Crane's poems and several of his prose works included in appendices at the end). Papers consist of miscellaneous writings by and about Crane, arranged alphabetically by subject heading.
  - WRITINGS
    - Collected Letters
      - Crane Letters, 1910-18 (Box 9, Folder 311)
      - Crane Letters, 1919 (Box 9, Folder 312)
      - Crane Letters, 1920 (Box 9, Folder 313)
      - Crane Letters, 1921 (Box 9, Folder 314)
      - Crane Letters, 1922 (Box 9, Folder 315-16)
      - Crane Letters, 1923 (Box 9, Folder 317-18)
      - Crane Letters, 1924 (Box 9, Folder 319-20)
      - Crane Letters, 1925 (Box 9, Folder 321-22)
      - Crane Letters, 1926 (Box 9, Folder 323-24)
      - Crane Letters, 1927 (Box 9, Folder 325-26)
      - Crane Letters, 1928 (Box 9, Folder 327-28)
      - Crane Letters, 1929 (Box 9, Folder 329-30)
      - Crane Letters, 1930 (Box 9, Folder 331-32)
      - Crane Letters, 1931 (Box 9, Folder 333-34)
      - Crane Letters, 1932 (Box 9, Folder 335)
    - The Letters of Hart Crane, 1916-1932
      - Final draft, typescript, n.d. (Box 10, Folder 336-62)
  - PAPERS
    - Articles on Hart Crane (copies), 1927-30 (Box 11, Folder 363)
    - Crane's poetry (copies), 1926, 1932, n.d. (Box 11, Folder 364-65)
    - Crane's prose writings (copies), 1918-32 (Box 11, Folder 366)
    - Crane's will (copy), n.d. (Box 11, Folder 367)
- Material from Other Sources, Dates 1913-32; Series V; 0.25; (1 box)
  Series V, Material from Other Sources (Box 12), is organized into two subseries: Correspondence and Writings.
  - CORRESPONDENCE
    - Brenner, Anita, 1931-21, n.d. (Box 12, Folder 368)
    - Cowley, Peggy Baird, 1931-32 (Box 12, Folder 369)
    - Cowley, Malcolm, 1923-32 (Box 12, Folder 370)
    - Josephson, Matthew (fragment), 1919 (Box 12, Folder 371)
    - Wiegand, Charmion von, 1919-28 (Box 12, Folder 372)
  - WRITINGS
    - Greenberg, Samuel B.
      - "Greenberg Mss", 1913-15, n.d. (Box 12, Folder 372a)
        Typescript copy by Hart Crane, with folder notes by James Laughlin
        See also: Correspondence, Box 5, folder 178
      - "Greenberg Mss" [additional poems], typescript and typescript carbon, 1915, n.d. (Box 12, Folder 372b)
- Oversize Material, 1923-29; 1.75; (1 box)
  - "Barreled Sunlight": advertisements, 1923-24, n.d. (Box 13, Folder 373)
  - "Community Plate": advertisements, 1928-29, n.d. (Box 13, Folder 374)
  - Glossy prints for illustrations of "Brief on Hart Crane and the Artists of Technology" with list of captions (Box 13, Folder 375)
- Restricted Fragile Papers
  Box 14, Restricted Fragile Papers, contains fragile originals. The material is arranged in folder order and may only be seen with the permission of the appropriate curator.
  Conditions Governing Access
  Restricted fragile material. Reference surrogates have been substituted in the main files. For further information consult the appropriate curator.
  - Box 6, folders 255, 275; Box 8, folder 305 (Box 14, Folder 376)
  - Box 8, folder 306 (Box 14, Folder 377)
  - Box 8, folder 307 (Box 14, Folder 378)